老板  在路上
Boss. On my way back.
上啊  上啊  未来战士
Work! Work, horsey!
顶住啊! 唉  糟了糟了
Crap. Hold on there. Damn it!
未来战士  顶住啊!
Hold on there, Terminator! Go!
哎呀  真是的
Come on!
我靠
Damn it!
糟了
Crap!
叫救护车呀
Help. Call... an ambulance.
你大爷的  真是未来战士啊?
Holy cow! Is this the freaking Terminator?
他奶奶的熊
God damn!
有追兵
There're persuers!
贺英接旨
He Ying, accept the imperial decree.
我贺英一向光明磊落
I have been upright and honest all my life.
不会做叛国之事
How would I do that?
冰封侠：重生之门
The Iceman Cometh
时空金球  乃婆罗国神物
Golden Wheel of Time is a sacred object from Borneo.
据《罗摩衍那史诗》记载
A Sindhu epic Ramayana says...
五千年前  婆罗国王子RAJU决战妖魔
5,000 years ago, Borneo Prince Raju left his country to fight with devils.
临别时  跟公主SAMA约定
Before leaving, he promised Princess Sama...
必于五星汇聚之时  平安归来
to come back safely when the five stars aligned.
惜战事延绵  公主误以为王子战死
But the war went on and on and Raju missed the day,
遂自刎殉情
Sama thought Raju was dead and killed herself.
王子得知湿婆神嗜爱七色阿修罗曼陀罗花
Raju knew the god Shiva loved rainbow Datura flowers,
续以心血灌溉  最终感动湿婆神
he then took good care of the plant and Shiva was touched.
乃赐予“鲁陀罗时空金球”
Shiva gave him "Golden Wheel of Time",
让王子穿越时空
a time travel tool,
返回五星汇聚之时  制止公主自刎
so that he could go back in time
有情人终成眷属
and stop Sama from killing herself.
时空金球  自此  流落人间
Golden Wheel of Time has been passed down among human ever since.
金球不能多于二人同用
Golden Wheel takes person back to
返到任何五星汇聚之时
the time when the five stars aligned.
所谓  五星汇聚  贯古穿今
The five stars aligning connects the past with future.
金球三转  法灭灰飞
Turn Golden Wheel thrice and it will self-destruct.
据说此球只可使用三次
The tool works for three times only,
有传RAJU皇子后人亦再用过一次
rumor has it someone apart from Raju has used it once.
故特敦促大明皇上三思
Thus, please advise the Ming Emperor...
善用最后一转
...to use the last shot wisely.
此乃何等神物?
What is it?
此物梵文称为LINGA
It's called Linga in Sanskrit...
相传乃湿婆神身上的阳物
believed to be Shiva's penis.
巨阳?
Enormous penis?
要启动金球  必须以LINGA导入
To activate Golden Wheel, you need to insert Linga...
配合密传口诀
and recite the secret mantra.
牛头! 马面!
Ox-head! Horse-face!
你奶奶的熊!
You bastards!
我贺英是命不该绝!
Tell Death God that it's not my time yet!
你们想把我带走是吧?
You want to lock me away?
没那没容易  马面!
Not that easy, Horse-face!
马面吃碗面不用挨打吧
What's your problem? I'm just eating my noodles.
小美  别过去啦!
May, don't go over!
别骚扰人!
Don't bother him.
是啊
Yeah.
锦衣卫!
Royal bodyguard!
(印语)快点啦  兄弟
(Indian) Come on man, hurry up!
(印语)不就在弄吗? 你这么急你来弄啊
(Indian) I'm on it right now, why don't you do it yourself?
(印语)现在你是老大话
(Indian) I'm the boss,
(印语)还是我老大啊? 这么多
just do what I said.
朋友  咖喱鸡  好味道!
Yo, curry chicken! It's good.
奶茶!
Milk tea, drink up!
别跑!
Stop running!
把盖子扔啦!
Drop those manhole covers!
散!
Run!
袭警啊!
Officers under attack!
现代的人身手这么差
Why are people nowadays so weak?
难道武功失传了?
Have martial art skills failed to be handed down?
还给我咖喱鸡
Give me back my curry chicken!
喂  不要动!
Freeze!
不许动!
原来这火枪这么厉害啊?
This gun is powerful!
三哥  我等了你大半天了
I've been waiting for you, Niehu.
你跑哪儿去啦?
Where've you been all this time?
饿死我啦!
I'm starving.
这对胸可不是开玩笑的
These are some serious boobies.
我还没看呢
Hey, I haven't read it yet!
我先看
Let me read first.
你又跟我抢?
Your turn first again?
大哥应该让着弟弟
You should give precedence to the young.
那贺英怎么办?
How about He Ying?
明天再找吧!
Let's track him down tomorrow.
这个更厉害  没穿裤子
Wow! This one is even better! She's pantless!
救命呀!
Help!
喂  这边  坐那儿
Hey, this way. Take a seat over there.
锦衣卫
Mr. Bodyguard!
我刚才请你吃面  现在请你喝酒!
I just bought you noodles. Now I buy you a drink.
今天晚上  我请客!
All drinks on me tonight!
太好了  谢谢!
Awesome! Thanks!
喂  英雄!
Hey hero!
刚才你打得真棒呀! 对吧?
It's so cool you kicked that guy's ass. Isn't it?
是啊  那个家伙老是骗酒喝  活该
That jerk never pays for his drinks. He deserves it.
这位兄弟
Bro...
待会儿再说
Later!
这位兄弟
Hey...
这里的人这么淫乱
People here are so licentious,
要浸猪笼啊
they ought to be drowned to death.
请问这里是什么地方?
Excuse me, where are we now?
兰桂坊呀
Lan Kwai Fong.
今夕是何时?
What year is it then?
现在是谁当皇帝?
Who's the Emperor?
干嘛你不停地问啊? 现在没有皇帝了
Why must you ask? There's no emperor now.
现在是中华人民共和国
It's 2013.
让我慢慢告诉你...
Let me tell you...
你说你自己是从明朝来的
You said you're from Ming dynasty...
明朝亡了之后呢
After Ming dynasty, there were...
明朝已亡?
Ming Dynasty has fallen?
想不到我贺英昏睡了四百年
And I've slept for 400 years?
皇上儿戏  满朝贪官
Young emperor never worked hard and corruption abounded.
蛮征暴敛  欺压人民  民变四起
Heavy taxes. Brutal oppression.
亡国乃迟早之事!
It's just a matter of time before rebels subvert the government.
当初先帝对我贺英  恩深似海
The late emperor had been kind to me
微臣护国不力  愧对先帝
I failed to protect my country. I pledge guilty.
微臣护国不力  罪该万死! 罪该万死!
I failed to protect my country. Guilty as hell.
这口井水又咸又臭
This well water tastes salty and stinky.
快点醒醒  有贼呀
Wake up. A thief broke in!
快点快点啦! 起来呀!
Wake up!
好脸熟喔!
He looks kind of familiar.
喂! 早餐到! 你们四个家伙干嘛啊?
Breakfast delivery! What are you guys doing there?
喂! 上面  看上面呀!
Look up! Up there!
英英  你在上面干嘛呢?
Ying? Why are you up there?
英英  别要打呀!
Ying, stop it!
我不是你所说的小肥呀!
I'm not the fat guy you talked about!
你这个狗娘养的畜生!
Damn you!
贺英接旨
He Ying, accept the imperial decree.
且慢! 先说清楚!
Hold it! Let's make this clear.
贺英你勾结倭寇! 怎么对得起兄弟们?
He Ying, you conspired with Japanese pirates. How could you let us down?
我何时勾结倭寇呀?
When did I conspire with Japanese pirates?
是你教我用剑  今日我就还给你!
You taught me sword fighting. Now I return the favour.
你干什么?
What are you doing?
兄弟之情到此为止
Ying, our brotherhood ends here and now!
二哥  皇命不可违!
Ying, you can't oppose to the Emperor's order.
我最痛恨的就是勾结倭寇
I hate people colluding with Japanese pirates.
贺英接旨
He Ying, accept the imperial decree.
奉天承运皇帝诏曰
By the mandate of heaven, this Emperor decree hereby.
原神机营提督御前侍卫贺英  辜负朕恩
He Ying, fourth-rank General of Royal Bodyguards, failed my expectations...
勾结倭寇
and conspired with Japanese pirates...
残害刑部尚书杜悦来一家老少七十六口
killing 76 lives in the minister of justice, Master Du's family,
手段凶残
by extremely brutal means.
今即褫夺官职爵位  交刑部严审
Now I strip him of power and office. He will be handed for interrogation.
如有反抗  格杀勿论
Anyone who resists this order will be killed.
钦此
Hitherto, by the Emperor himself.
我贺英一向光明磊落  不会做叛国之事
I have been upright and honest all my life. How would I do that?
你自己跟他说!
You speak up!
当日  就是你贺英  迫我勾结倭寇的!
It's you who forced me to conspire with the Japanese pirates.
狗娘养的畜生! 分明是你陷害我!
Damn you! You are clearly framing me for treason!
既然如此  我唯有当面和皇上对质!
I have to meet his majesty and
还我清白!
clear myself of the accusations.
通倭者罪诛九族
Treason gets all your close and extended family members executed.
皇上已令精骑南下
His majesty is sending a squad of
杀尽桃园村全体男女老幼啊
elite soldiers to Taoyuan Village for execution.
哈哈哈
Hahaha...
先帝在上!
The late Emperor in heaven...
我贺英  绝不能让家乡的亲人无辜被杀
I, He Ying, can never let innocent people be killed.
恕微臣不敬!
Forgive me for my disrespect.
就这样  他们几兄弟被雪活埋了
That's how the they got buried in snow.
我没有说漏吧  英英?
Did I miss anything? Ying?
寻秦记呀?
Like in "Back to the Future?"
肥兄!
Chubby!
叫我Slander
Call me Slander.
史兰大兄  刚才我认错人
Mr Slander, I was a bit confused just now...
打错了你
and used more violence than needed...
算了算了
You're forgiven.
刘邦!
Liu Bang!
我帮你打给刘邦  他一定能帮你!
I'll call Liu Bang for you. He sure can help.
好! 那我就打给他儿子刘备!
I'll call his son Liu Bei.
那我打给谁呀?
Who should I call then?
你打电话给刘德华啦!
Call Andy Lau.
你们这帮三八这么没有义气呀
Girls, are you leaving me?
喂! 怎么你几个这么没有义气呀
Are you leaving just like that?
其实呢...我看他真的很可怜
He's so pathetic...
你家里这么大
and you can't use up all this space yourself,
不如...你收留他吧
why don't you let him stay?
你脑壳坏掉啦?
What's wrong with you?
被他打傻了?
Did he crush your brain?
我跟他孤男寡女  怎么可能收留他?
He's a guy. How can I let him stay?
史兰大兄
Mr. Slander.
两位热情同款待  在下心领了
I sincerely thank you for your hospitality,
时候也不早了
but it's getting late and
我也不想再耽误大家的时问
I don't want to take up your time.
至于小美姑娘的一饭之恩
Miss May, I'll forever remember
我贺英  铭记于心
your kindness for the lovely meal.
告辞
Farewell.
英英  你就这样子出去啊?
Ying, you're leaving just like that?
你的造型怎么能上街啊?
How can you go out in that look?
啥型啊?
What look?
你的打扮呀! 难道是你的台型吗?
Your appearance of course.
在照什么啊  照照照照照?
Are you missing a mirror at home?
死跑龙套的
Stupid extras.
要拍戏去电视城找乐小姐嘛!
Go to the TV station and ask for Oprah if you want a job.
哼!
Hmm.
容许我跟你商讨一下  好吗?
Young man, give me a minute to discuss with you.
想怎样?
What do you want?
你奶奶的熊
You bastards!
干! 我一定要学咏春
I must learn martial art!
老板  你想借机找陈嘉媛对吧?
Boss, you want to date a martial artist this time?
靠!
Damn!
这么个破狗头拍高了50倍
They bid up the price 50 times on that stupid dog head.
这次我肥啦
I'm a rich man!
一千两百万欧罗
12 million Euros.
立刻给我转四千八百万  到邓先生户口
Transfer HK$48 million to Mr Tang's account immediately.
知道!
Got it.
所以说呢  做生意一定有个好拍档
Having a good partner is everything in running a business.
我跟你合作了这么久  从来不用我操心
Ever since I worked with you, I don't worry about a thing.
对了  有件事想问你
By the way, let me ask you.
上次那三个冰尸的事...
Those three frozen corpses last time...
会动的嘛!
They were alive, right?
是呀! 会动的!
Yes, they were!
不会动  北韩姓金的
Kim the North Korean wouldn't spend
也不会花这么多钱买他们
a fortune on them if they weren't.
研究长生不老的秘诀
He's so obsessed with staying alive forever.
但你怎么知道的?
But how did you know?
开车的这么碎嘴
The driver can't keep his mouth shut.
他跟你说的吧?
He told you, right?
他是出事了才会告诉我
He only told me after the accident.
他不只和你说  他喝醉了还跟个妞说
Not only did he tell you, but his girlfriend as well after drunk!
你问他  还有多少人知道?
Ask him. How many people knew about it?
问!
Ask!
对不起! 对不起呀!
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
你说得对  做生意最重要找到个好拍挡
You said it right. Having a good partner is everything in doing business.
不用我再操心
so that I don't worry about a thing.
自己的事  自己搞定
Your own problem. Solve it yourself.
把地方收拾干净  给你的
Clean it up after him. A gift for you.
谢谢老板
Thanks Boss.
小美  你今晚好性感喔
Hey May, you're looking hot tonight.
有火吗?
You got a light?
你这样就不对了
You shouldn't have done that.
你...
Hey! You...
小美姑娘  举手之劳
Miss May, you don't have to thank me.
我贺英  曾经受过小美姑娘你一饭之恩
I've accepted your meal and I'm grateful.
昨天听说你经常被人轻薄
Last night you said you've been harassed,
所以我贺英特地来教训这帮淫贼
that's why I came to teach them a lesson.
你在这里干嘛?
What the heck do you think you're doing out here?
老板  我不认识他的
Eh... Hi Boss, eh... I don't know him.
喂  你干嘛打人呀?
Hey you! Why did you beat them up?
我只是点了他们的穴
I only strike their acupoints.
看! 没事的
Look. They're fine.
你朋友?
Is he your friend?
他不是我朋友!
He's not my friend!
怎样也好  你们跟我来把话说清楚
No matter what, you two are coming with me to settle this.
我不想其他人看到我们在这里打架
I don't want everybody to see us fighting out here.
这番邦女人骂你什么啊?
What did this foreigner scold on about?
谈判啊  你别跑了
Negotiation! Come on.
不可以再打人了
Don't hit people anymore.
你的男朋友打伤我的保镖
Your boyfriend beat up the bouncers.
这样闹事会影响到生意
That'll make trouble and it's not good for business.
你要赔钱给他们才能解决事情
You have to pay them to settle this.
她想怎么样?
What did she want?
赔钱呀  粉肠!
Money! Idiot!
什么是“粉肠”?
What's "idiot?"
你先别说话  让我来处理
Hush and let me handle it.
你的烂摊子自己搞定
He's your problem, deal with it.
请你先冷静
You can calm down a little bit.
冷静? 冷静你全家
Calm? Calm the heck!
你这个番邦女人! 一开口就骂人父母
You foreign pig! Cursing others right from the start.
嘴真臭!
So disrespectful!
明明是你纵容一帮淫贼  欺负良家少女
You manage your staff poorly and let them bully a decent woman,
还要她赔钱?
and dare ask for compensation?
我帮你赔
I'll pay for you.
我帮她赔
I pay for her.
你真好啊
Really? You're so generous!
够了吧!
Is this enough?
什么东西  开玩笑吧?
What's this? You joking?
不认识银票是吧?
You haven't seen it before?
好  我还有
Okay. How about this?
金子你认识吧  你奶奶的熊
You must've seen gold before.
先生请你点算一下
Sir, here's your cash.
劳烦了!
Thank you very much.
拿去
Here you go.
这些我就给老板娘  这些是你的!
I'll pass this to my boss. And these are for you.
小心收好呀  香港坏人很多的
Keep it safe. There are many bad people in Hong Kong.
财不可外露!
Don't flash the dough.
你把钱全都给了我  那你不是没钱旁身?
You gave me all this and leaving yourself penniless?
我还有!
No, I still got plenty.
还有?
Plenty?
不用担心! 你看!
Look. Don't worry.
你到底还有多少啊?
How much have you got?
不如一次全都卖了吧?
Let's sell it all at once.
香港坏人多  财不可外露
There are many bad people in Hong Kong. Don't flash it.
麻烦你  帮我把这两锭金也买了
Excuse me. I want these two ingots in cash please.
笨死了
Stupid!
好的  请稍等
Just one moment please.
先生呀  你的玉能否让我见识一下?
Sir, may I have the pleasure to take a look at your jade pendant?
这块老坑玉晶莹剔透
This ancient jade is gorgeous and
而且龙还刻得这么生动
the craftsmanship is exquisite.
是明朝的御用精品
It's artisan jewelry of Ming Dynasty.
真让我大开眼界
It's an honour to have seen it.
那你不如把这也卖了吧
Why don't you sell it as well?
你们出多少钱呀?
How much will you pay for it?
小姐  你不是开玩笑吧?
Miss, you must be kidding, right?
我们哪收得起呀?
How can shops like us afford it?
你要拿去苏富比拍卖才行
Maybe Sotheby will sell it for you.
这块玉  保守估计值几千万的!
This jade pendant is worth at least tens of millions dollars.
几千万?
Tens of millions?
我这块玉实不相瞒
To be honest,
是当年先帝  御赐给我的
this jade pendant was given to me by the late Emperor,
无价之宝
I'm not selling it for anything.
先生请点算一下
Here's your cash, sir.
不用了
Thank you so much.
谢谢...
Thank you. Thank you.
请  请
So long.
小美姑娘  这里附近有没有客栈呢?
Miss May, is there any hotel around here?
还住什么客栈呀? 太见外了
Why are you staying in a hotel? You're treating me like a stranger!
我们是好朋友  来住我家
We're friends and you should stay with me.
那我就不客气了  我还以为你不会问了
Well, I accept then. I'm afraid you wouldn't offer.
拿点吃的来  快点
Bring me some food. Make it quick.
(印度语)去准备些咖喱菜式
(Indian) Go prepare some curry dishes.
老四  这个西洋火器  威力惊人
Sao, these western weapons are so powerful,
我们一定要...在他开枪之前先下手为强
we must fire before our enemy does.
不然  以我们两个的武功修为
Or else, even with our strength and agility,
一丈之内  也会被它击毙
we can't dodge it if shot from within 3 meters away.
你说呢?
What do you say?
就用它来对付贺英吧
Let's use it on Ying.
大哥
Boss.
这里的...意粉...咖喱...鸡真的不错喔
The curry... chicken spaghetti here is not bad.
三哥  是咖喱...鸡...意粉!
It's spaghetti chicken curry.
咖喱鸡意粉
Spaghetti chicken curry?
是呀!
Yes yeah!
是嘛?
Yeah?
是呀!
Yeah!
下令所有人去找!
Ask all our people to find this man.
(印度语)全部人跟我出来
(Indian) Everybody, come with me.
(印度语)我们出去找人!
We must find this man.
以后你就睡这里
You'd sleep here from now on.
香港寸金尺土  地少人多
Hong Kong has little land but many people. Floor space is very expensive.
我就收你5000块一晚  绝对超值
I'll charge you a special rate of HK$5,000 a night.
钱不是问题
That's fine.
我当年行军  也是天为被地为席
I slept outdoors in the army.
只要...暂时让我有地方落脚
Now I have a roof over my head,
我真的是感激不尽
I'm eternally grateful.
那就最好啦  我跟你说一下
It's good that you make do with it. Let me tell you.
那间是我的房间  不能进去
That's my room and you can't go in.
当然
Of course.
其他地方都是共用的  随便
But feel free to use all other spaces.
看电视看韩剧都可以
Watch TV or a movie if you want.
有什么需要就告诉我
Just let me know if you need anything else.
虽然我知道你需要钱
I know you need money.
但是做人别这么过分
But don't go too far.
别以为人家是明朝来的就好骗
Don't scam him because he's from Ming Dynasty, okay?
这些你都不用管
That's not your business.
你要做的就是留下来给我壮胆
All you have to do is to stay here for the night.
你也知道他神经兮兮的
Who knows what he'd do at night. Keep an eye on him.
你看到没有? 一步都不能走开呀
See? Don't even look away for one second.
这个还不是你们的现代乐器?
It must be a modern musical instrument.
音韵很...扑朔迷离呢
It sounds quite... dreamy.
这个是我们现在的高科技
It is cutting-edge technology.
电子琴
An electronic keyboard.
小美姑娘  原来你喜欢玩乐器
Miss May, so you like playing musical instruments?
但现在就是个摆设
But now it's just here for decoration.
我小时候没学好  现在年纪大了
I didn't put much effort when I was young. Now that I'm old,
手指不听话了  想学也太迟了
I can't even move my fingers swiftly. I guess I'll give up.
我认为做人只要有坚持和信念
I believe that, anyone can do anything
定会滴水穿石!
with insistence and faith.
英英  昨晚你不是说翻车才来到现代的?
Ying, you said a truck overturned and brought you here.
但是我找了一晚上  都没找到这条新闻
I sought through all sources, but I don't find this piece of news.
新闻...
News is...
是啥?
Yes?
我们的官府消息呀
...information from our government.
这是何物?
What's this?
平板电脑
A tablet.
你要查什么  手指划一划就行了
Just swipe it with your finger. You can almost find anything.
他奶奶的熊
What the heck.
区区小小的铁板  竟能知过去未来?
A small piece of metal that tells the past and future,
比我们大明的永乐大典厉害百倍
so much stronger than our encyclopedia in Ming Dynasty.
是不是用这个铁板  就可以帮我找线索?
Can you find the clues for me with it?
当然可以啦!
Absolutely.
没有桃园村喔
There is no entry on Tao Yuan Village.
要不找找鲁陀罗时空金球?
Let's search "Golden Wheel of Time".
那英英就有机会回到明朝了!
Ying can go back to Ming Dynasty if we find it.
好主意!
Good idea.
小美姑娘  有劳有劳
Miss May, quick.
是...
Okay...
也没有时空金球
Nothing on Golden Wheel of Time either.
看来时空金球  已经跟我一起长埋于雪山
I guess Golden Wheel of Time was buried in snow just like me.
要不然...用你的名字试一下?
How about... searching your name?
好呀
Sure.
竟然这么写? 胡说八道!
How could they write such a thing? It's all nonsense.
他奶奶的熊! 他奶奶的熊!
Those bastards!
喂! 你看看
Hey. Come and read.
贺英  天启二年
He Ying colluded with Japanese pirates
勾结倭寇
in the 2nd year of the Tianqi Reign.
其后熹宗诛其九族
His close and extended family members were executed by the Emperor.
史官评之为天启年问
The official historians commented him
奸臣之首
as the most treacherous official of Tianqi Reign.
怎么办呢?
What should we do?
风波亭中  武穆蒙冤
In Wind-Wave pavilion; Yue Fei was framed.
杜鹃泣血  唯恨千古
Azalea wept in bloody tears; sorrows lingered on for thousand years.
他奶奶的熊
How ridiculous!
他奶奶不会是真的有只熊吧?
I hope he's alright.
让工匠马上打造出来  明白吗?
Find a blacksmith and make this. Understand?
明白
Okay.
老四  其实...凶手是否真的是贺英呢?
Sao, actually... could the murderer be someone else?
一定是他
Impossible.
当晚杜大人设宴  就我们四个人
There were only the four of us at Du's.
小胖他都承认了
Chubby admitted his crime.
证据确凿  没什么好说的
The evidence was crystal clear. There's nothing to discuss.
杜大人  今晚宴请我们是否...
Master Du, you invited us here tonight.
有要事商讨?
Is there something you want to discuss?
我们捉到一个奸细  在他身上
I got secret intelligence and seized a bunch of letters
搜到一封通倭寇的密函
written to the Japanese pirates.
内容说我们有自己人
There must be a spy in the army,
把机密出卖给倭寇!
selling out our intelligence to the Japanese pirates.
让我知道是谁  我一定将他碎尸万断!
If I find out who he is, I must tear him to bits!
我最痛恨日本人的了!
I hate Japanese!
密函虽无所名  但只要我们核对字迹
Letters were not signed. But we can find out who he is...
这样一定可以找出内奸
if we compare the handwriting.
诸位大人  贺大人  报
Officers, General He, salute.
有何事? 快讲啊
How was it? Tell us.
大人  你下令运往桃园村的粮饷财帛
The money and food you ordered will be sent to...
明早可以出发
Taoyuan Village tomorrow.
好  做得好
Good. Well done.
就在当晚  杜大人全家76口都被杀了
76 lives of Mr. Du's family were killed that night,
第二天早上  贺英就离开了京城
and He Ying left the Capital the next morning.
密函也跟着消失了
And the letters were nowhere to be found.
真的是证据确凿
That's some evidence, huh?
贺英
He Ying,
我是不会放过你的
I won't let you off the hook!
我的咖喱鸡意粉呢?
Where's my spaghetti chicken curry?
郭小姐  我们真的很忙
Ms Kwok, we're so busy here.
打给你不听  留言不回  支票又弹票
You don't answer calls or return messages. Your cheques were bounced.
你这样很没礼貌
It's very impolite.
不好意思...
I'm terribly sorry...
我知道你很孝顺
I know you care for your mum.
但孝顺也要量力而为
But you should do it within your means.
如果真需要的话  去申请综援吧
If you need it, apply for social security.
但不会是我们这个档次的了
Of course the homes won't be of this class.
就连何先生也叫四姨太来这里询问过
The fourth wife of Mr. Ho came and asked if she could send him here.
我都没有位置给他
I couldn't even squeeze her a room.
陈院长  你给我一次机会吧
Director, please give me one more chance.
这次是最后一次  下不为例
This will be the last time. That's it.
谢谢你...
Thank you!
妈  你今日好漂亮喔
Mum, you look gorgeous today.
这两天刮风呀  你冷不冷?
It gets cold these couple days. Do you feel cold?
冷要告诉我呀
Let me know if you do.
我带了你最喜欢吃的鱼片粥
I made your favourite fish congee.
记得小时候...你经常煮的
You always made me fish congee when I was little,
现在轮到我煮给你吃了
now it's your turn to try mine.
来  小心烫呀  呀
Watch out. It's hot. Ah...
张开嘴巴  呀!
Open up! Ah...
再来  再来  喔
Once more.
好棒啊!
That's great!
您独自一人把我养这么大
You raised me up all by yourself.
每天晚上又要做女工  累到双眼都瞎掉了
Doing needle work every night which blinded you.
我怎么求你陪我进京你都不肯
You won't come with me to the Capital even I begged you to.
我都不知道该怎么办了
I don't know what else to say.
傻孩子
Silly!
你将来衣锦还乡
All villagers and I will be proud of you
我跟桃园村的村民  都会以你为荣啊
when you set for glorious homecoming in the future.
你放开我妈! 放开她呀!
Let go of my mum! Let her go!
七叔呀  你干嘛打我呀?
Uncle Seven, why did you hit me?
是吗? 没有呀
What? I didn't.
妈  你说话了?
Mum, you're talking!
你们搞什么啊?
What happened?
伯母阴阳失衡  经络偏歪
Your mother suffered from Yin-Yang imbalance and crooked meridians.
导致神智不清
That's why she's unconscious.
我刚才只是帮她疏通血气  顺理经络
I just cleared the blockage in energy and blood flow for her.
让我再帮她多弄几遍  她肯定会更舒服
She'd feel even better if I do it to her a few more times.
谢谢你  随便弄几遍也行
Thank you so much, please do that again some times.
尽量吧
Will do.
妈  你记得我吗? 我是小美呀!
Mum, remember me? It's May.
不记得了  我只是记得七叔偷了我的母猪
No, I don't. I just remember Uncle Seven stole my pig.
妈
Mother
黄天在上  明月当前
In the name of heaven and the moon,
我贺英仅向当天折刀为誓  纵然历尽百劫
I, He Ying, swear by my sword, despite all hardship,
我必重返大明
I must return to the Ming Empire...
护我桃园村上下
...to protect Taoyuan Village...
免我村民为我冤枉而死
...and save my relatives from being massacred
如有违誓  势必千刀万剐
Breaking my vow, I must die with a million wounds,
死无葬身之地
without a proper grave.
我的双立人钢刀!
My Damascus knife and
还有我的古巴雪茄! 你把它当香来点
my cuban cigars!
没事...
Okay...
我刚才是为了你救村民的决心而感动
I was deeply moved by your pledge to save the villagers just now,
所以你随便赔两万块就行了
so I'll only charge you HK$20,000 for that.
难得姑娘深明大义  我贺某  不胜感激
For your understanding, I express my deepest gratitude.
天一亮我们就开始调查  好吗?
We'll start investigation first thing in the morning, okay?
好
Okay.
老伯  慢慢吃  别急
Eat slowly. Take you time.
那晚看见什么?
What did you see that night?
我只是...见那家伙撒尿  射得很远
I saw that guy pee, long range.
不是普通远  是非常远
Not just ordinarily long range, but very freaking long.
他飞得很高  不是普通高  是非常高
He flew high. Not just ordinarily high, but very freaking high.
从现在开始  你什么都没见过
From this moment on, you've seen nothing.
如果他找你  打电话给他
If that guy shows up, give him a call.
喔
Okay...
别浪费  吃光了再走
Don't be wasteful. Finish all food before you go.
神僧说  贺大人命中注定  将逢巨劫
The Divine Monk said, General He was destined to have major mishaps.
究竟是什么劫难?
What kind of mishaps?
生而复死  死而又生
you'd live and die, and live again.
七日之后  五星汇聚之时
In 7 days, the five stars will align.
贺大人的人生将有巨变
Your life will see major changes.
那就是会即将降临?
That means it'll happen very soon.
非也  要很久很久
No. It takes a long long time.
此乃跟时空金球一并流传后世
Here are the 7 Datura seeds that were passed down...
硕果仅存的七粒曼陀罗花种子
with the Golden Wheel of Time.
神僧决定将它转赠给你留念
The Divine Monk decides to let you have them.
种子注定会落入有缘人手中
They are brought to you by fate.
佛经有云  只要有芥子草那么小的阻力
Someone will move Mount Xumi...
就可以移动须弥山
with his small but strong will.
到时有人会转生曼陀罗花
When that person successfully grows Datura flowers,
奇迹就会发生在你身上
miracles will happen to you.
因即果  果即因
A cause is the effect. An effect is the cause.
种是因  结是果
You sow the seeds, You reap the fruit.
至于是因是果  那就要看贺大人的造化
Whether it's cause or effect, it all depends on your karma.
是5400年前的种子? 现在还能种到吗?
Seeds from 5,400 years ago, do they still sprout?
你奶奶...
Come on...
小美  怎么你这么久都也不看妈呀?
May. How come you didn't show up for so long?
妈! 你记得我了?
Mum, you recognise me?
你以为妈傻掉了? 自己女儿都不认识!
You think I'm crazy or something? How can I not recognise my daughter?
七叔  你的玉好漂亮呀!
Uncle Seven, your jade pendant is so pretty.
如果我百年归老  送给我陪葬可以吗?
When I die, will you let it be buried with me?
那可没机会  你这么长寿
Well, you'll live long and I'm afraid that won't happen any time soon.
神僧曾经告诉我  我人生必有七劫
The Divine Monk told me I must experience 7 mishaps.
生和死...我都经历过啦
I've experienced... life and death.
我来到这个世界必有原因
There must be a reason for me to be here.
我很想知道我种出什么果
I need to know what fruit I'd reap.
如果是这样的话
I believe the seeds...
这颗种子我觉得好快就能发芽
will sprout very soon.
谁说的?
How do you know?
你教我的嘛  只要坚持  定会有奇蹟
You told me, miracles happen... as long as you insist.
这个真好吃! 这个咖喱鸡很好吃  对吧?
Delicious! This curry chicken is really good.
鸡?
Chicken?
鸡
Chicken.
这是咖喱什么?
Curry what?
咖喱鱼蛋
Curry fish ball.
咖喱...咖喱鱼蛋
Curry... Curry fish ball.
随便啦
Whatever.
咖喱...咖喱鱼蛋
Curry... Curry fish ball.
怎么还没到妓院?
Are we anywhere near the brothel yet?
你怎么这么心急
You seem so horny.
你不明白400年没行房的感受啊
You won't understand how it feel not having make love for 400 years.
先找个妞培养一下感情
Let's warm up by talking with the girls first.
然后再进房  那怎样玩都行
You can do whatever you want in the room later.
那这里的姑娘...会不会弹琴吟诗啊?
The girls here... do they play music and dance?
弹琴是不会  但吹吹箫就很厉害
Not music. But they know how to blow.
你的老相好来了  来  Tina  Vincy
I bring your favorites... Tina and Vincy.
嗨!
Hi.
请问你  有没有皮肤...
Excuse Me, do you have girls with paler,
白一点  滑一点的?
smoother skin?
有有有  我马上帮你找
Of course I do. I'll go look for you.
你过来  再找再找
You come here. And look for more.
来  过来坐
Come sit over here.
老板  这两个就够白  够滑吧
Bosses, they are pale and smooth enough, right?
一个叫西西  一个叫雯雯
Xixi and Wenwen,
快跟老板打招呼
say hi to the bosses.
嗨  老板
Hi bosses!
这两个够滑也够白了  但我要一个...
They are pale and smooth, but I want...
肚子...窄一点  就是...那种...腰身
their waist to be... less wide, ...more skinny.
好好好  我马上帮你找
Sure, I'll go and look.
来来来  这个我喜欢
Hey come over. This one is hot.
过去过去
Xixi, go.
老板你好
How are you, boss?
叫我西西就好了
I'm Xixi.
老板老板  你看
Bosses, I bring you
我这次可把两个镇店之宝带过来了
the most wanted girls in store.
这个是Ada  这个是阿情
This is Ada, and this is Ching.
不错喔
Not bad.
快跟老板打招呼
Hello.
你好
(日文)晚上好  我是情  请多多指教
(Japanese) Good Evening, I'm Ching, Nice to Meet You.
东洋魔女  我要报国仇家恨!
Japanese frail! It's time to pay back what you owe our nation!
我最痛恨日本人的了!
I hate Japanese!
老四! 老四! 冷静点!
Sao! Stop it!
东洋婊子!
You Japanese frail!
老四! 老四! 冷静点!
Calm down, Sao.
你大爷的神经病啊! 我是中国人!
You crazy! I'm Chinese!
我不会做你生意的!
I'm not doing business with you!
苍井空又是哪的?
By the way, what about Sora Aoi?
是世界的
She belongs to the world.
准备好了吗?
Are you ready? Okay.
5  5  10  20
Five. Five. Ten. Twenty.
我来跟你猜拳
Let me play with you.
好啊  你要多喝点
Alright, you gotta have some more to drink.
当然
Yeah.
你这样就不行啊?
You're wasted.
让我来
Let me.
我们现在试用的这套人面辨识系统
We're trying this new face recognition system
是由美国太空总署研制
developed by NASA.
美国中央情报局也在用
CIA is also using it.
这套系统很贵
It's very expensive and
财委会还未通过拨款
we haven't got the budget approved by Finance Committee yet.
系统会把一个人的轮廓  五官  比例
The system divides a person's face, features,
分成超过一百四十七组数据进行分析
proportion into 147 sets of data for analysis.
连结了CISCO的超级电脑
It's connected with the Cisco super computer.
我们就能随时追踪监控
We can track and monitor all close-circuit cameras
政府所有的闭路电视
owned by the government,
和巡逻警员身上通话器的镜头
and the cameras on the walkie-talkie of all constables.
只要有80％吻合  就极有可能是同一个人
A match of 80% or above means it's very likely to be the same person.
系统就会马上找出这个目标的所在地
The system will instantly find out the location of the target.
警官  早!
Good morning, sir!
警官!
Sir!
给我找这三个人
Find these three guys for me.
警官  系统只能用来找通缉名单上面的人
Sir, the system is for those on Police wanted list only.
你怎么知道他们不是通缉犯呀?
How did you know they're not wanted?
不在名单上面就不是通缉犯吗?
Can't they be wanted even if they're not on the list?
是不是所有内部资料你都要知道?
You have to know all internal intelligence?
以后我给你报告好不好?
Should I report to you from now on?
上环那件杀警案  就是这几个怪人做的
These guys killed our officers in Sheung Wan.
因为这件事警方很没面子
It's a major loss of face for the police.
我们要低调处理  明白吗?
We have to play it down. Okay?
明白  马上输入电脑
Understood. Input the info at once.
是!
Yes, Sir.
我不想留在这儿  回去不就是等死
I don't want to stay here. I'm just waiting to die.
我的病都已经好了
I'm not sick anymore.
我记得呀!
I remember you.
你是七叔  你是小美嘛!
You're Uncle Seven. You're May.
妈  所以你要乖  要听话
Mum, be a good girl.
你的病还没有全好  要留在这里
You haven't fully recovered. Stay here, okay?
我没事! 不用你照顾
I'm fine. You don't have to take care of me.
这里每天都有人死的  我很怕有鬼
There's someone dying here every day. It's a haunted place.
我闭上眼睛也睡不着
It's a haunted place. I close my eyes and I can't fall asleep.
哎哟
Oh.
想怎样!
What now?
那要看你的表现咯
Let's see how you behave.
伯母  你乖乖的  好好在这里疗养
If you stay here being a good girl,
不要让小美担心  你好点了我答应...
so that May doesn't have to worry, I'll give it to you
给你!
when you get better.
七叔  你别骗我老太婆
Uncle Seven, you can't lie to an old woman like me!
我怎么会骗你? 好歹我也是大明御前侍卫
I'll keep my promise. I'm a royal bodyguard from Ming Dynasty.
对啊  妈  七叔不会骗你的
Mum, Uncle Seven won't lie.
真的?
Really?
当然
Of course.
好吧  回房  回房
Okay, let's go back to my room.
七叔  下个星期我回家
Uncle Seven, when I have my vacation next week,
你要做羊肉饺子给我吃!
I want you to make lamb dumplings.
什么饺都可以
What ever you like
好! 有羊肉饺子吃!
So happy. I want lamb dumplings.
那你要乖乖听话喔
Be good!
先生  请问你住哪?
Mister, your home address please.
别烦我了  走开  走开!
Don't bother me. Get lost.
电台  5007  over
Station, it's 5007, over.
怎么样?
What is it?
警官  目标位置在
Sir, target seen on Castle Peak Road,
青山公路岭南段及虎地一带
near Lingnan and Fu Tei sections.
黄教授!
Professor Wong.
张警官
Commissioner Cheung.
你上次跟我说的印度史诗《罗摩衍那》
I kept reading the Sindhu epic Ramayana you mentioned last time.
我怎么都看不明白
But I didn't have a clue.
其实很简单
It's simple.
印度教的其中一个主神叫湿婆
Shiva is one of key Hindu deities.
訑的生殖器官叫做LINGA
His penis is called Linga,
LINGA就代表了创作力  生命力
which represents creativity and power of life.
从祂的史诗来说  湿婆跟乌玛交媾
According to the epic,
一交配就交配了一百年
Shiva copulates with Madhura for 100 years.
众神惊讶她的生命力这么强
The deities saw his vigor and virility,
就建议湿婆
suggesting that...
把那些精液  注射在恒河里
...he squirt his sperms in Ganges,
让恒河周围的地带变得肥沃
so that land around the river would be fertile.
既然LINGA是神力的象征
As Linga symbolizes holy power,
所以时空金球的启动
I'm sure Golden Wheel of Time...
我很肯定  一定需要LINGA来启动
has to be activated with Linga.
谢了
Thanks, Professor.
谁呀?
Who is it?
啊!
Huh?
飞虎队到了以后  就采取行动
Take action as soon as SDU arrives.
喂  我是阿鹏
Hey. It's Pang.
听说那只未来战士
Eh... I heard the horse called Terminator,
马主说可以下注了
the horse owner said go ahead.
准备现金啊
Hey. In cash, okay?
这次赢定了!
We must win this time.
喔
Yes.
借茅厕一用
Is that your toilet? Let me use it.
我搞定了!
I nailed him.
我把他锁到里面了!
He's locked inside!
行动!
Action. Go.
我要现金呀  现金呀!
Give me cash. Cash!
撑住
Hang in there.
全面开火
Fire at will.
现金呀!
Cash!
糟糕了!
Holy cow!
他大爷的!
弄得我一屋都是屎!
My place is covered in faeces!
在那儿!
Over there!
我靠!
Damn it!
你干什么呀?
What are you doing?
你不是说这古玉是皇上赐给你的? ?
Didn't you say the jade pendant was from the Emperor?
我答应过送给伯母  大丈夫一诺千金
I promised your mother I'll give it to her. I'm just keeping my word.
谢谢
Thank you.
你知不知道  我跟我妈
When we first came to Hong Kong,
刚刚来香港的时候  是怎么样的?
we had a really hard time.
那时  只要一开口说国语
As soon as I spoke Mandarin,
所有人都会瞪着你
everyone would stare at me.
那种被歧视的感觉  真的好难受
Discrimination really hurts.
在京城  只要说不同的口音
Back in my days, if you use a different dialect...
冰糖葫芦也会卖贵两文钱
in the Capital, everything is marked up by 20%.
我们是一种很奇怪的动物
We are weird xenophobic beings.
人好多时遇到跟自己不同的人
When we come across people who are different from us,
就会群起欺负
we join forces and bully them.
这是本性
It's human nature.
最后我唯有把自己扮成从美国回来的海归
Years later, I pretended to be overseas Chinese living in Hong Kong.
现在想起来都觉得很可笑
Now that I think about it, it's just ridiculous.
我骗人  说谎
I lied...
就是想多赚点钱
just to make more money...
给我妈治病钱
for my mom's treatment.
就是想她生活过得好一些
I just wanted her to live a good life.
其实你不需要过分自责
Don't blame yourself.
正所谓生死有命
It's destiny.
伯母是一个豁达  开朗的...小朋友
Your mother is a happy-go-lucky kid.
我相信她在天之灵也很希望看到你
I'm sure up there in heaven,
开开心心的过日子
she still wants you to live on happily.
对吗?
Right?
伯母  我是七叔呀
This is Uncle Seven.
你是不是很想小美  开心的过日子呀?
Do you want May to live on happily?
别只顾着傻笑  你自己跟她说
Don't just laugh. Tell her yourself.
妈  我答应你
Mum, I promise,
我会好好生活
I'll live on happily.
大声点! 伯母耳背!
Louder! You mom doesn't hear that well.
妈! 你听得到吗?
Mum! Can you hear me?
我会好好的!
I'll live on happily!
你放心吧
Don't worry.
小美会好好过日子的
Your daughter will live on happily.
自从最低薪水实施以后
Since the implementation of minimum wage,
说实话  多少商铺餐馆倒闭呀!
countless number of shops and restaurants closed down.
我们当老板多么辛苦!
How tough it is to stay afloat?
想到头发都白了!
Owners are thinking so hard that our hair turns gray.
不是我们? 那帮伙计哪有工开啊!
Without us, where can workers find a job?
社会要进步  不是有本事的人
In a progressive society, those capable
去救济没本事的人
are not supposed to subsidize those incapable.
说
Speak.
警官  追踪到去立法会议事厅
Sir, target location, Legislative Council.
没本事在香港生活  就回大陆!
Those not capable enough to live here, go back to mainland.
吃屎去吧!
Or rotten to death!
救命啊!
Help!
救命啊! 救命啊! 有人要杀我!
Help! Someone's after me!
邓先生  上车
Mr. Tang, get in the car.
邓生麻烦你稍等
Mr Tang, please wait here.
张警官正赶回来
Commissioner Cheung is rushing back.
警局的东西哪是人喝的? 去星巴克
How can you serve me drinks from canteen?
给我买杯拿铁  要低脂
Go get a latte from Starbucks for me. I want it low-fat.
请各地区同事注意
Attention please, all officers.
留意一名中国籍男子
Please pay attention to a Chinese man...
身穿红色恤衫  黑色西装外套
wearing red shirt and black blazer.
中等身材  束长发
He's of medium build with shoulder-length hair.
最后发现位置在立法会大楼
He was last seen at LegCo Building.
此男子极度危险
This man is very danger.
请各地区同事注意
Attention please, all officers.
留意一名中国籍男子
Please pay attention to a Chinese man...
身穿红色恤衫  黑色西装外套
wearing red shirt and black blazer.
中等身材  束长发
He's of medium build with shoulder-length hair.
最后发现位置在立法会大楼
He was last seen at LegCo Building.
不好意思
Oh, sorry.
多谢
Thank you.
司徒警官  你搞什么?
Officer Szeto, what are you doing?
你吃过什么啊?
What did you eat?
喂  不是我!
Hey, it's not me.
喂! 我的拿铁呢? 拿铁呢?
Hey! Where's my latte? My latte?
殊! 别吵! 别吵!
Hush! Be quiet!
痛不痛呀?
Does it hurt?
痛就对了
Well, it should.
为什么把我运来香港?
Why did you send me to Hong Kong?
你说什么啊?
I don't know what you're talking about.
那你看见我跑什么?
Then why did you run when you saw me?
你长得这么丑  凶神恶煞  是人都跑啦
You look hideous and violent. It's only natural to run.
你奶奶的熊
Are you bluffing me?
靠!
So? Ouch!
你给我一点时问
Give me a minute.
我请师傅来  到时候绝对不会怕你!
I'll ask deities to possess me. I'm not afraid of you.
奉请太上老君赦令  急急如律令
I beg Taishang Laojun, urgently and righteously.
关圣帝君现真身
Guandi please show your true self.
桃园三结义  忠义万古存
Oath of the Peach Garden; loyalty and justice last forever.
面赤心亦赤
My face and my heart are red;
须长义更长
my beard is long and my righteousness is even longer.
等一下  我会用我的分筋错骨手
I'll use my Sinew-splitting and Bone-dislocating trick on you.
把你身上的筋络移位  肌肉抽描
Your meridians will mess up, muscles twitching,
筋骨互磨
sinews grinding against bones.
从来没有人在这招下不招供的
No one can ever stand this gruesome torture without telling the truth.
关二哥我出手了!
Guandi, here I come.
斩颜良  诛文丑  过五关
Executing Yan Liang; killing Wen Chou; passing 5 gates...
好痛呀! 你大爷  好痛呀!
This freaking hurts... Ouch... This freaking hurts!
恕我出手重了  二哥  冒犯了
Forgive me for using too much force. Excuse me, Guandi.
二哥走了
Guandi is gone.
是谁运我来香港的?
So, who sent me here?
是有人叫我这么做的...
Someone told me to.
谁呀?
Who?
不能说  说了会没命的
I can't tell. I'll get killed if I do.
他叫张一呜  副警务署长
He's Cheung Yat-ming, Deputy Commissioner of Police.
我走私的拍档
He's a partner of my smuggling business.
警官  我尝试用地名索引锁定目标
Sir, I'll use Gazetteer to lock on the target.
好
Good.
说
Speak.
张警官  找到目标
Commissioner Cheung, we located the target.
在哪里?
Where?
在总部的VIP房里
In the VIP lounge, Police headquarter.
回总部
Back to the headquarter.
救命呀! 救我呀!
Help! Help!
使劲啊  没吃饭呀?
Thrust harder. Have you guys not eaten?
你们听清楚  封锁所有出口
Listen. Block all exits.
任何人都不让进出
Don't let a single soul in or out.
是的  警官
Yes, Sir.
混蛋! 你们想撞我死呀?
Idiots! You want to crush my head?
师兄! 师兄!
Are you okay?
张一鸣为什么要把我挖出来?
Why did Cheung Yat-ming unearth me?
我不知道呀
I don't know.
我只知道要把你们三个运到香港来
I was only responsible for transporting the three of you here.
还有两个?
There are two more?
他们两个跟你的打扮一样的
They look just like you.
他们两个在哪?
Where are they now?
鲁陀罗时空金球呢?
Where's Golden Wheel of Time?
你说的是天竺神碟吧?
Do you mean the Sindhu Saucer?
东翼后门已经封锁
The rear exit of East Wing is sealed off.
张警官  他在MS胁持着邓先生
Commissioner Cheung, he's holding Mr Tang hostage.
我们不敢攻进去
We dare not break in.
混蛋要不要我教你怎样做?
Idiot! Were you born yesterday?
他问你什么了?
What did he ask you?
没说  没说  什么也没说
I said nothing. Nothing at all.
你没说? 你不怕痛吗?
Nothing? Aren't you scared of pain?
有没有见过他呀?
Have you seen him?
没有呀  走开了
No... Get lost!
各位各位  这位大侠你们谁认识呀?
Hi everyone. Anyone knows this hero?
我欠他钱我要还给他
I owe him money and want to repay him.
谁帮我找到他  赏一万块
Cash reward of HK$10,000 for anyone who finds him.
我欠人钱我睡不着觉
I can't sleep well when I'm in debt.
啊?
What?
那有这种好事? 拿来看看
Cash? I don't believe it. Pass it over.
喂  好像你男朋友
Hey, he looks like your boyfriend.
他哪里像我男朋友呀?
Nonsense!
别开这种玩笑了
Don't crack jokes on things like that.
看仔细点  他是否你男朋友?
Look closely, is he your boyfriend?
不是啦  真的是你男朋友喔
Oh yes, this is definitely your boyfriend.
真的是他
It's really him.
哪里像他啊?
No way.
你喝多了  你喝多了
You're drunk! You're drunk!
根本就是他  为什么说不是?
That's him, why don't you admit it?
你别管了
Don't make a scene.
来喝酒
Drink.
我先  10  10  5  15
Me first. Ten. Ten. Five. Fifteen.
10  20  20  10  10
Ten. Twenty. Twenty. Ten. Ten.
你是...贺英!
You are... He Ying!
是谁的?
Who's phone?
喂! 别玩了哈比人
Hey midget. Stop messing with us.
拿来!
Give it back.
是不是你的?
Is this yours?
干嘛? 你以为你凶神恶杀
What the hell? You think I'd budge
我就怕了你呀?
because of your scary face?
有种你过来!
Come here if you dare!
贺英  我终于找到你啦!
He Ying, you show up at last.
滚开
Get lost
醒醒  醒醒啊!
Wake up! Wake up!
醒醒  醒醒!
醒醒啊! 追上来啦!
Wake up! They're closing on us!
口诀? 你不早说?
A mantra? Why didn't you mention it earlier?
我差点杀了他!
I almost killed him!
新发现嘛
It's a new discovery.
小姐  病人是你什么人?
Miss, what's your relationship with the patient?
我不认识他  我刚才在街上
I don't know him. I saw him pass out
见他昏倒了  就把他送过来了
on the street and took him here.
你帮我跟进  好吗?
Please follow up on this case.
好的
Okay.
你跟我去登记一下资料  好吗?
Please come over. I need to write down your personal particulars.
好
Sure.
警官  找到目标  100%吻合
Sir, target found. 100% match.
这两个家伙什么情况呀?
What's happening to these two?
一会儿发冷  一会儿发热?
Fever this moment. Hypothermia the next.
最奇怪的是验血报告
The blood test is even stranger.
他们竟然对这几百年的流行病
They don't have antibodies for epidemics
完全没有抗体
occurring in the past few hundred years,
就好像是外星人一样
just like space aliens.
护士
Nurse?
给他们打最厉害的抗生素万古芬素
Give them shots of the strongest antibiotics Vancomycin.
如果有特别反应  再打这支镇静剂
If they have abnormal response, give them this tranquilizer too.
喔
Okay.
喂  肥婆
Hey fat woman.
打万古芬素  下手太重了吧?
Prescribing Vancomycin? You don't think it's too strong?
我怕有什么古怪的传染病像沙士那样
I'm afraid it's some strange contagious disease like SARS.
到时候大家的楼价就得跌
My house will be worth much less if property prices dive.
张耀辉  请到分流站
Cheung Yiu-Fai, please report to distribution station.
喂! 干什么呀?
What're you doing?
你们救醒我三哥了吗?
Have you saved my brother yet?
谁是你三哥呀?
Who's your brother?
就是刚才才送来的那个
The one I sent here just now.
你要是救不活他  我也救不了你!
If you can't save him today, I can't save you either!
放手呀!
Keep your hands off me!
我们身为医生  对每一个人
We have to save every one of our patients.
都一视同仁
We have a fair medical system here,
所有人都要救的!
we treat every patient without discrimination.
每一个人的生命都很宝贵  你明白吗?
Each and every life is equally precious. Got it?
医生  算了
Doc, calm down.
关你什么事啊?
None of your business!
大夫
Doctor,
那我三哥什么时候会醒?
then when will my brother wake up?
一个小时后
An hour later.
来  吃包子  是牛肉馅的
This one's for you. With beef patties.
这里不准吃东西!
Food is not allowed here.
如果你要吃东西  要不出去吃
You either get out of here and stuff your face...
要不乖乖地坐在这里  慢慢等
or sit here quietly and wait.
别在这里大吵大闹  好不好!
Don't yell and scream. Okay?
谢谢  不用客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
不用客气
You're welcome.
好的
Okay.
看什么看  走吧!
What're you looking at? Keep walking!
做事  做事
Nothing to see here. Get back to work.
有什么事啊  警官?
What's the matter, officer?
王凤仪请到2号房
Wong Fung-Yee, please go to Room no. 2...
请等一下
Hold on a sec...
小妹
Junior.
是
Yes?
两个病人醒了之后帮我打镇静剂
The two patients just woke up. Give them a shot of tranquilizer.
好的
Okay.
今天4楼好忙碌喔
There's so much work to do here on the 4th floor.
快醒来...快点醒来!
Wake up! Wake up now!
醒醒  醒醒!
Wake up!
水～! 我要喝水!
Water! Give me water!
快点!
Quick!
你是...你是那个
You... you're that...
警官  就是这两个
Sir, these are the two injured.
他是极度重犯  我要把他带走
This is an extremely dangerous criminal. I need to take him with me.
是的  警官
Yes, sir.
警官  那这个呢?
How about this one?
非法入境而已
Just an illegal immigrant.
你先带他回去
You escort him to detention centre.
是的  警官
Yes, sir.
快醒来! 醒醒!
Wake up! Wake up!
追杀你的人已经在外面!
Those assassins hunting after you are right outside.
你快点醒过来!
Wake up!
我要拿那两个非法入境者的随身物品
I'll take the personal belongings of those two illegal immigrants with me.
跟贺英一起的女的在这里  他一定在这里
The girl with He Ying is here. He is definitely here too.
咦? 醒了?
Oh, he woke up already?
还有一个呢?
Where's the other one?
你快告诉我  怎么恢复体力?
Tell me. How to give him an instant boost of energy?
早睡早起  饮食定时
Sleep early. Wake up early. Eat regularly.
晒太阳和多喝点水
Sunbathing. Drink more water.
这里好像是大动脉吧?
This is your main artery, right?
肾上线素
That's adrenaline.
此乃何等神物?
What is it?
此物梵文称为LINGA
It's called Linga in Sanskrit...
相传乃湿婆神身上的阳物
believed to be Shiva's penis.
巨阳?
Enormous penis?
要启动金球  必须以LINGA导入
To activate Golden Wheel, you need to insert Linga...
配合密传口诀
and recite the secret mantra.
因金球只赠当今大明皇帝
Golden Wheel is offered to Ming Emperor only,
故金球奥秘绝不能对任何人泄漏半句
you can't disclose this secret to anyone else.
神僧请放心  我用我的性命担保
Please rest assured.
我绝不会向任何人泄漏秘密口诀
I swear on my life that I won't let anyone know the mantra.
你奶奶的熊
Damn you!
LINGA呢?
Where's Linga?
LINGA被警察拿走了
Linga? The police took it.
追
Let's go.
警官  搞定了
Sir, all done.
三哥  在那边!
Niehu, there they are!
开了场啦
It's show time.
锁匙锁匙
Key
追!
Follow them!
上车  快!
Get on! Quick.
张警官  目标离开了医院
Commissioner Cheung, target has left the hospital,
路线往荃湾西方向
running toward Tsuen Wan West.
把Linga交给我
Bring me Linga.
知道  老板
Yes, Boss.
张警官  疑犯到了青马大桥
Commissioner Cheung, target reaches the Tsing Ma Bridge.
要不要封锁现场?
Would you like to seal off the area?
不用  等我  我正过去
No. Wait for me, I'm on my way.
老四  你搞这么长时问
Sao, it takes you forever.
你到底会不会啊?
Do you know what you're doing?
三哥  你别吵了  搞得我心都乱了!
Niehu, stop nagging. It's really distrubing.
你神经病啊?
Are you nuts?
喂  醒醒!
Hey, wake up!
有没有搞错啊?
What the heck?
再说我揍你啊
Shut up or I'll beat you up!
我的宝贝!
Oh my baby!
贺英!
He Ying!
帮手
Give me a hand
看!
Look.
有只马
There's a horse.
喂  你看
Hey... Look.
不用害怕
Don't be afraid.
放我们出去呀!
Let us out!
一起帮忙吧!
Give me a hand.
先看看他
Look at him.
别着急  很快就没事了
Don't worry, things will be alright.
救命呀!
Help!
贺英  你的手已经废了
He Ying, your arm is crippled.
你怎样打呀?
How are you gonna fight?
老四!
Sao!
来来  快点走  快点!
Come on, let's go! Quick!
三哥!
Niehu!
小心呀!
Be careful!
二哥!
He Ying!
贺英  贺英!
He Ying! He Ying!
大哥!
Yuanlong!
他没死
He's alive.
我们抓到一个奸细  在他身上
I got secret intelligence and seized a bunch of letters
搜到一封通倭寇的密函
written to the Japanese pirates.
内容说我们有自己人
There must be a spy in the army,
把机密出卖给倭寇!
selling out our intelligence to the Japanese pirates.
大哥
Yuanlong.
为什么要杀嫣妍?
Why did you kill Yanyin?
阿虎!
Niehu!
阿狗!
Sao!
贺英勾结倭寇! 以后我们怎么办?
You conspired with Japanese pirates. What will become of us all?
我贺英一向光明磊落  不会做叛国之事!
I've been upright and honest all my life. How would I do that?
当日东厂查出行凶者所用的
Intelligence found out the murderer
是你的独门武器
used your unique weapon.
贺英! 你不单只通倭卖国
He Ying, not only did you betray our country,
还背弃我们兄弟的感情!
but also our brotherhood.
我们兄弟这么多年  想不到今日...
We've been the closest friends all our life.
竟然如此陌生
I can't believe you're such a stranger to us.
元龙
Yuanlong.
到!
Here.
贺英
He Ying.
到!
Here.
聂虎
Niehu.
萨獒
Sao.
气聚丹田  暗藏内劲  发!
Build inner power in lower abdomen. Squirt!
谁不知道我们四兄弟是
Who doesn't know we're
全京城撒尿最远的?
the longest range pissers in the Capital?
好
That's right!
你奶奶的熊
Damn right!
而且是打仗杀敌最勇猛的四个呀!
And the strongest, bravest fighters too!
够了吗? 走吧!
Done? Let's go.
走啦  大哥!
Brothers, let's go!
走!
Go!
驾!
如果这个金碟  真有穿梭时空的功能
If this saucer really is a time machine,
我跟你先走
you and I will go first.
但是这样做会不会改变历史?
But will it change the history?
明朝还是不是我们熟识的明朝呢?
If we go back to Ming Dynasty, would it still be the Ming Dynasty we know?